Latinx Center Records UA224
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Latinx Center Records
circa 1980 -- 2018
circa 1992 -- 2018
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Latinx Center
UA224
3.6 Linear Feet
1 Web sites
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Latinx Center. 2018, accession UA-2018-050.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series by format: Web crawls; Photographs; ALAS Yearbooks; Historical materials; Administrative records; and Videos.
Biographical / Historical
The Latinx Center was founded in 1993 as the Hispanic American Center to provide emotional and structural support to the Latinx, Caribbean, and Latin American students at Tufts. In 1998, the Center changed its name to the Latino Center to provide better identity and representation, and on September 15, 2020, became known as the Latinx Center, representing their ongoing efforts to create a space that is "equitable and inclusive for all students." Originally located at 55 Talbot Avenue, the Latinx Center has been on 226 College Avenue since 2000.
The Center was initially led by Rubén Stern, who served as Director for 24 years. He was succeeded by Julián Cancino (2017-2019) and Marvin Casasola (2020- ).
Beginning in the late 1990s, the Latinx Center has been affiliated with the Association of Latin American Students, the Latino Peer Leaders Program, the Tufts Society of Latinx Engineers and Scientists, and special interest housing, La Casa Latina. The Association of Latin American Students (ALAS) is a student-run organization that holds weekly meetings to discuss issues in the Latino community. The Latino Peer Leaders (LPL) Program assigns upperclassmen that identify as Latinx, Caribbean, or Latin American to first-year students. As a mentor, the LPL provides guidance and support throughout the year. Tufts Society of Latinx Engineers and Scientists (SOLES) supports minorities majoring in STEM fields. La Casa Latina is one of Tufts' six special interest housing options, open to juniors and seniors.
Scope and Contents
This series contains materials documenting people and events related to the Latinx Center, including crawls of the Latinx Center website, photographs, scrapbooks, newsletters and clippings, administrative material, and video recordings.
Student Affairs and Services; Student life; Student activities; Student activism
- Web crawls, 2015 -- 2018; UA224.001; 1 Web sites
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains crawls of the Latino/Latinx Center website.
  - Latino Center at Tufts University, 2015 -- 2018; UA224.001.00001; Latinx Center
    General
    Frequency: quarterly crawl. (Inactive)
- Photographs, circa 1990 -- 2016; UA224.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains photographs and negatives of people and events related to the Latinx Center.
  - Photographs, 1994 -- 1994; UA224.002.001.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Photographs, 1997 -- 1997; UA224.002.001.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1998 -- 1998; UA224.002.001.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1999 -- 1999; UA224.002.001.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2000 -- 2000; UA224.002.001.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2001 -- 2001; UA224.002.001.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2002 -- 2002; UA224.002.001.00007; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2003 -- 2003; UA224.002.001.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2004 -- 2004; UA224.002.001.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2010 -- 2010; UA224.002.001.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2012 -- 2012; UA224.002.001.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1990 -- 1995; UA224.002.001.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 2000 -- 2010; UA224.002.001.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 2003 -- 2003; UA224.002.001.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 2005 -- 2005; UA224.002.001.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 2010 -- 2011; UA224.002.001.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 2011 -- 2012; UA224.002.001.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Ice Skating Trip, circa 2001 -- 2004; UA224.002.001.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Latino Peer Leaders, circa 1994 -- 2012; UA224.002.001.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Photographs from scrapbook, circa 1994 -- 2000; UA224.002.001.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Films, negatives, photographs, circa 1994 -- 2005; UA224.002.001.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Cuba Experience, 2002 -- 2002; UA224.002.001.00022; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Latinola Retreat and Peer Leaders, 2004 -- 2016; UA224.002.001.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 1994, circa 1990 -- 1994; UA224.002.001.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 1995, circa 1991 -- 1995; UA224.002.001.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 1996, circa 1992 -- 1996; UA224.002.001.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 1997, circa 1993 -- 1997; UA224.002.001.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 1998, circa 1994 -- 1998; UA224.002.001.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 1999, circa 1995 -- 1999; UA224.002.001.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2000, circa 1996 -- 2000; UA224.002.001.00030; 3 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2001, circa 1997 -- 2001; UA224.002.001.00031; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2002, circa 1998 -- 2002; UA224.002.001.00032; 3 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2003, circa 1999 -- 2003; UA224.002.001.00033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2010, circa 2006 -- 2010; UA224.002.001.00034; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2014, circa 2010 -- 2014; UA224.002.001.00035; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Class of 2015, circa 2011 -- 2015; UA224.002.001.00036; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
- ALAS Yearbooks, 2000 -- 2005; UA224.003; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  This series contains unofficial "yearbooks" created by the Latinx Center, with photographs, notes, and other memorabilia.
  - ALAS yearbook, 2000 -- 2001; UA224.003.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - ALAS yearbook, 2001 -- 2002; UA224.003.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - ALAS yearbook, 2002 -- 2003; UA224.003.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - ALAS yearbook, 2003 -- 2004; UA224.003.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - ALAS yearbook, 2004 -- 2005; UA224.003.002.00005 (Box 2)
- Historical materials, 1992 -- 2017; UA224.004; 25 Folder(s)
  This series contains newsletters, clippings, and related documentation of the Latinx Center.
  - Historical material, 1992 -- 1993; UA224.004.003.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1993 -- 1994; UA224.004.003.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1994 -- 1995; UA224.004.003.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1995 -- 1996; UA224.004.003.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1996 -- 1997; UA224.004.003.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1997 -- 1998; UA224.004.003.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1998 -- 1999; UA224.004.003.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 1999 -- 2000; UA224.004.003.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2000 -- 2001; UA224.004.003.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2001 -- 2002; UA224.004.003.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2002 -- 2003; UA224.004.003.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2003 -- 2004; UA224.004.003.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2004 -- 2005; UA224.004.003.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2005 -- 2006; UA224.004.003.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2006 -- 2007; UA224.004.003.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2007 -- 2008; UA224.004.003.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2008 -- 2009; UA224.004.003.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2009 -- 2010; UA224.004.003.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2010 -- 2011; UA224.004.003.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2011 -- 2012; UA224.004.003.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2012 -- 2013; UA224.004.003.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2013 -- 2014; UA224.004.003.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2014 -- 2015; UA224.004.003.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2015 -- 2016; UA224.004.003.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
  - Historical material, 2016 -- 2017; UA224.004.003.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3)
- Administrative records, 1995 -- 2014; UA224.005; .3 Linear Feet
  University records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
  This series contains binders of administrative material relating to the Latinx Center, including material concerning governance, budgeting, event planning, and membership.
  - Administrative records, 2007 -- 2008; UA224.005.003.00026 (Box 3)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Administrative records 2008-2009, 1995 -- 2009; UA224.005.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Administrative records 2009-2010, UA224.005.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Administrative records 2011-2012, UA224.005.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Administrative records 2013-2014, UA224.005.003.00030 (Box 3)
- Videos, circa 1980 -- 2002; UA224.006; 16 Video Recordings
  This series contains video recordings of events at the Latinx Center, as well as video recordings used by the Latinx Center.
  - Journey into Exile by Carlos V. Gutierrez, 1998 -- 1998; UA224.006.003.00031; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Edward James Olmos at Tufts - 1997, 1997 -- 1997; UA224.006.003.00032; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Rita Moreno Talk 10/17/2001, 2001 -- 2001; UA224.006.003.00033; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Video, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00034; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Video, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00035; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Rita Moreno Lifetime-Intimate Portrait, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00036; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Many Stories Panel 2002, 2002 -- 2002; UA224.006.003.00037; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Cesar Chavez, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00038; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Many Stories '97-98, circa 1997 -- 1998; UA224.006.003.00039; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Story Performances "Face to Face" 19:45, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00040; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Olmos II, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00041; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Video, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00042; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Video, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00043; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Firing Line Debate "Resolved: The U.S. should lift the Cuban trade embargo", circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00044; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - El Vez-Rey Del Rock and Roll, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00045; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)
  - Video, circa 1980 -- 2000; UA224.006.003.00046; 1 Video Recordings (Box 3)